Quiet on the set. And we're rolling.
现场安况，并始拍摄
Cody Maverick interview, take one.
故酷弟芒谈，第一次
Why are you guys here to interview me?
你们干嘛来探切我?
It's what we do. We're a reality film crew.
这是工作，我们拍纪人月
Should I know some of the questions before we start?
我是不是该先看过问题 ?
-No. They're easy. -Okay.
-不用，很简章的 -好吧
-Can you stand on that box, please? -Oh, yeah.
-请你站到箱子上好吗? -好啊
Right there? What is that?
这里唉?那是什么?
-What is that? -A sound thing. It's a microphone.
-那是什么 ? -收音用的，雁克风
What's up, man? I'm Cody.
你好唉? 我是酷弟
And you're what, 14, 15 years old?
你多大? 1 4、15城?
Seventeen years of age.
我芳龄1了
And any other skills besides surfing?
除了街浪你还会做什么 ?
Like what? Like singing and dancing?
什么意思 ? 唱歌跳舞吗 ?
Yeah. Yeah.
是啊
No, not me, man. I just surf.
不喜欢，我只本浪
-Loser. -[ just--
-庆物 -我只是…
Cut it out, Glen. Stop, man.
好了，可人，别并了
We're here to make a movie about Cody.
这部月的主角是酷弟
-Does he have to be here? -It's gonna be great.
-他一定要在这儿吗?9 -我很上相耶
Can I get in line now to not see it?
演的时候拜旗别送我标
We'll re-slate.
我们重来
Since we're talking about surfing, give us your thoughts about surfing.
谈到本浪，说说你的看法吧 !
Surfing. Surfing.
生浪、衡浪
-Where do I start? -How about at the beginning?
-和从何说起呢? -就从头说吧
Okay, well--
好吧 ! 这麻说咀…
So as soon as there was the first wave, right? There was the first surfer.
打从地球出现第一道浪 就有人街浪
All they needed was, like, a piece of driftwood...
他们只需要一月浮木
...@ block of ice or something like that, and then they were off.
或一块冰…之类的 他们就上了
And they were hooked, man. They were hooked,
然后会沉迷，会上净哩
Up till recent times, you had your old dudes. Your hang-six cats.
直到你叔朱伯伯的年代 那些街浪达篇
These old guys used to lay down with these huge, humongous boards.
那些老头都玩超策重浪板
These guys were the pioneers...
他们算是先锋
..but nobody saw what surfing could really be...
但没人见识过竺浪的属害，直到…
until Big Z did it.
乙钟大显身手
-Could you tell us who Big Z was? -Who was Big 2?
-说说民捉是谁吧 ? -乙钟是谁?
You're asking the right guy. You got that far. Z is everything.
你问对人了“，贡好唆 乙钟是神
Big Z is surfing. 1 mean, he's--
他就是本浪
There may well as not have been an ocean before Z.
没乙印可能就没海
They invented the ocean for him.
海浪为他而生
He lived so hard because he wasn't afraid to live.
他挑战生命，因为他热爱生命
He wasn't afraid to die.
他甚至不怕死
He came to Antarctica when I was just a kid.
他来南极时我还是个小毛编
Man, it was the biggest thing that ever happened here.
那可是这唯一发生过的大事
And suddenly there he was.
突然问他就来了
Just floating over the water. Hovering, you know, like weightless.
就那样杜洋过海 水上溧，像有去功一样
He could've walked up to anyone...
他大可以走向任何人
..and he walks right up to me.
他分直接走向我
And he gives me this awesome, one-of-a-kind Big Z necklace.
给了我这人条超酷限量乙钟项急
And then he tells me, "You know, kid, never give up.
“和孩子，永焉别放于
Find a way, because that's what winners do."
找到出路才是赢家“
He was the greatest.
他是最伟大的
Everyone looked up to him, respected him, loved him.
每个人都很崇拜他 尊阁他、过他
And one day, one day I'm gonna be just like him.
有一天 有一和天，我也会像他一样
And I've been surfing ever since ! can remember.
从我有记居开始，我就在街浪了
It's hard to imagine my life when I wasn't surfing.
很难想像我有什么时候没在生浪
! want to get out of here, and this is my ticket out.
我想郊天这里，这是我的机会
I'm really good, man. I'm the best on the island.
我很行 我是这里的生浪王
! know it sounds cocky for saying that, but, ! mean, I am, like the best.
这样好像很臭屁 不过这守就我最尾
Lived here my whole life.
我一英子没出过国
That's where they sort the fish. It's the dumbest thing I've ever heard of.
那是把急分类的地方 那是我孤过最大的事了
But yeah, I worked there just to pacify my mom a little bit.
我在那里工作 只是为了安括我婧
This place sucks, bro.
问到不行
l worked my way up from the sardine pile, then to the mackerel pile...
我从基属做起 从沙丁急部门，赔升到青花急部
..and l ended up on the gefilte fish pile.
现在升到急丸部
-All hard work. -Not like some I could mention.
-都是靠苦力 -不像有些编哩
Yes, this farkakte kid with the thing on the water.
那个只会在水上打混的臭小子
My house?
我家?
Over there. You see it right there with the surfboards?
就在那，气很多街浪板的那问
Yeah, I just live here with me and my brother, Glen, my mom.
我跟老哥可人和我老妈一起住
He was a little, teeny, small egg.
酷弟出生时小得像难蛋
He wasn't very impressive.
长得又没特别钙
Glen was the big egg, Cody was the small egg.
可人是大蛋，酷弟是小蛋
He can't help it. That's just the way he is.
没闪法，长那样能怪谁
I mean, he's out there...
酷弟整天泡在水里
..in the water all day shirking his responsibilities.
打混又不负责
You know, hatching these eggs is a big responsibility.
要知道，孵蛋是重责大任
And my brother, Cody, he just doesn't understand that.
而我老弟酷弟就是不明白
-He needs to step up and be a man. -It takes a real man to sit on an egg.
-是男人就该站出来 -孵蛋的才是正港的男子汉
-You know it. -Quincy, come to Daddy.
-说的好 -快肉脚，和爸苑在这壬
He wants to be different. All the time with the different.
他想与夷不同，成天作怪
Who's got the time in the day to--
谁有那种美国时间啊
Only six months in a day.
这壬一天才只有六个月耶
-Thanks for making it. -Sorry. It was too good to miss.
-谢谢你赶来 -歹势，刚才在浪头上
-How was it out there?
-外面好玩吧?
He's the big brother. I'm the little brother.
他是大哥，我是小弟
I'm not touching you.
我没惟你
-Not gonna touch you. -Do you see this?
-谁要蕉你啊 -你看到没?
-Don't. Please? -I'm not.
-不要闻啦 -我没啊
He makes sure that I know that.
他老是过欺负我
! had to fight for everything. Even Mom's tuna casserole.
我什么都得用抢的 包括老妈的一中好菜
I'm lucky I survived.
能活著算我命大
It really wasn't that easy for him growing up.
他能长大真的很不容易
Like I said before...
我说过
..he never really knew his father.
他连他老区都不太记得了
I'm not really the person to ask about it because I was too young to remember.
其实这不该问我 我当时太小了，不记得了
Look, I'm not the only kid on the island...
镇上又不是只有我的老爸被.. .
.. whose dad was, you know, eaten.
吃掉
-Still, it had to be traumatic. -No. Not for me, bro. Not for me.
-你应该还是很鸡通吧 -不会，我不会
-What's your dream? -To go away.
-你的枕想是什么? -准开这里
-To go away. That's great. -Do you guys want a drink?
-郊天这里，真好啊 -要喝点什么吧?
Got to run away from responsibility and life.
-想逃避责任，放素人生 -酷弟，他们不要人饮料
This is unique.
今天很反常
-This is not the norm. -" have dreams."
-平常不是这样 一“我有萝想
-When is this not happening? -Don't make that noise.
-现在是怎檬? -别发出怪声音
-Cody! -It's really disrespectful.
-酷弟 -没礼貌
I would never do that.
我就不会那样
You just wouldn't make it out of your mouth.
因为你都是用屁股发言
That's the difference between you and me.
那就是我们不一样的地方
You know what? I can't do this anymore.
你知道叶? 我受金了
Mom. Look what you did.
妈 ! 你看都是你啦
This is for me. This isn't for you. Why is Glen still here?
被抬切的是我不是你 可人怎短还不走?
Oh, yeah, exactly. Mom!
我也不想来 ! 妈!
! don't understand why everybody's so judgmental.
我不知道大家堤嘛这广党啥我
! understand why Mom's judgmental.
我知道我妈为什么叭我
! think it's because she cares, partially. It's also partially because...
我想有部份是因为她在乎 还有一部份是因为
.. everyone else is looking at her like, "Hey, Cody's just a bum.
大家都让她党得酷弟很没用
Cody's this. Cody's that. Cody's this."
说酷弟这样不好、那样不行
Cody's me, bro. Let me be me.
我就是这榜，我想做我自己
When is that gonna start?
我还要忍受多久?
You know what they call me? The dream maker. The dream maker.
大家都叫我圆萝大使 萝大使
I find these kids, I bring them here...
我发据这些孩子，带他们来这
..and l give them a chance to be somebody.
给他们机会出人头地
You know my greatest joy as a surf promoter? Finding Z.
我最大的成就 就是发据乙钟
Watching him rise to the top.
看著他街上烽峰
! still can't believe he's gone. He was like a son to me, you know?
我还是不能接受他死了 他就像我儿子
It was a heart thing, you know? Can we just take five minutes?
我痛不欲生啊，心痛的哩 休息五分饼好吗 ?
How's my hair? Is it messed up? l ain't got all day. Is it mussed?
我头权乱吗 ? 我很忙的 六哎啦，梳好没?
We just have a few more questions about Big Z.
我们只想问妈个关於乙印的问题
But right now I think we're more interested...
但现在，我想观玲更想知道
..in the Reggie Belafonte story, and who could blame us?
我雷大克的亲功伟业，没错吧?
But Big Z is kind of the focus of our--
不过乙钟才是重点…
Let's get the coconut filler guy over here.
那来药问个水小弟好了
And how about the guy sweeping the sand?
还是那冰抬地的阿桑?
Can we hear your boring story about your tedious, ridiculous life?
谈谈他们小鼻子小眼睛的人生吧
Get your feathers off it! Stop!
把那世毛拿天 ! 住手!
l ain't got all day. I got a big production here.
我很忙的，我奸有大活动要搞
Roll, okay? Just roll!
快拍 ! 拍就对了
Welcome, fans, to another edition of SPEN Sports.
炊迎收看SPEN朵育台
This is Sal Masakela...
我是主播沙茶鸭
..and we're here at the surfing capital of the world, Pen Gu Island...
现在我们来到生浪天堂企头岛
..for a preview of the tenth annual Big Z Memorial Surf- Off.
为您抢先报导第十届的 “2Z 钊本浪球^
Professional surfers extraordinaire...
让职业街浪高手 薛凯子和轧小九
...what challenges our surfers are going to face.
来介绍选手们将面对的宣战
First things first, Sal. The wave. It's the perfect combination...
最首要的就是海浪
..of beauty and danger. Even the pros are terrified of this place.
这壬的海浪美导中藏著危险 就束职业选手看了都怕
Dig this, Sal. Section behind me.
我身后是著名的
It's "The Boneyards." Few surfers have ventured in there...
“九扔十入芍 选手进去十个有八个
..and come out alive.
是横著出来
Are you trying to tell me people have died here?
你是说有人在里面送命?
-That's right, Sal. -A moment of silence for them.
-没错 -让我们一起默亡
And we keep it moving because if the Boneyards was not enough...
继续我们的报考 如果“九拐十入艾”过了
..our surfers will be facing off with Tank "The Shredder" Evans.
选手们还得应付“杀手”坦克
Tank, nine-time defending champ.
坦克，蜡联九届和酝浪冠军
A role model? No.
我的偶像 ? 没有
But I do consider myself somebody that everyone should look up to.
不过我认为大家应该崇拜我
Kids should try to pretend that they're Tank.
小朋友至少要假装他们是坦克
I mean, they should try. Good luck, kids.
多少装一下，小鬼加油唆
You never want to get in there and help them out...
你从来不想去帮助小孩 教他们怎订衡浪
..and show them how to surf and spend some time with the kids?
花可时间跟小孩相处 ?
No, I don't want to do that.
没，我不来那套
-Anyway, this is my wave. -Always classy Tank Evans.
-我的浪来了 -这就是区坦克
Coming up after the break, penguin dodge ball. Stick around.
广告后请继续收看 《猴急躲避球》
Okay, to get back to the competition, I just want to say:
好的，回头说“2Z 钙和酝浪祭“
I'm scouring the globe for the next big thing.
我上天下海挖掘明日之星
But that's another story.
不过那又说来话长了
He doesn't look for them. I find them.
他才汪去找，是我去找
I find these penguins. I find the talent.
我找来这些企钨选手 我长据明星
Reggie has sent me everywhere on this trip.
我老阅雷大克派我走透全球选秀
Anyplace there's an ocean...
只要有海
..@ lake, a puddle. It's ridiculous.
有湖的地方都去，超拉
! amon so much migraine medication, you have no idea.
我把头痛药当人饭吃，很主张吧
The stress is killing me. I don't know how much longer I can last.
我压力大到爆 老实跟你讲
I have to tell you that right now.
我不知道我还能撑多久
You gotta try this blowhole thing, man.
你一定要试试这管
This whale dude is giving me a brain freeze.
这入鱼在让我脑袋瓜吃思乐冰
I lost a bet.
我一定没烧好香
Excuse me. Excuse me.
借阅一下
Does anybody in this entire frozen wasteland surf?
这冰天北大荒的有人和酝浪吗?
-The Cody Maverick kid does that. -Wonderful. Thank you.
-难酷弟那小子会 -非常好，感谢您
You know, you're sitting on... thin ice.
你知道你屁股如履…薄冰
Excuse me, I'm looking for-- I'm looking for Cody Maverick.
不好意思，我在找帮酷弟
-Has anyone seen Cody Maverick? -I'm Cody Maverick.
-有人看到故酷弟吗? -我就是套酷弟
Mike Abromowitz from the Big Z Memorial Surf-Off, Pen Gu Island.
我是企头岛“Z负生浪朱″”星探米基
You came here on a wha-- You came to see me. Wow!
你是来…你来找我，哇
-Quite a slip-and-slider, aren't you? -You're here. What an honor, sir.
-你还是售滑润儿吓 ! -你亲自来议，真是楷幸
Lovely. Wonderful. l hear you surf.
很好，很妙，贡说你会生浪
-ls this true? -You gotta see what I can do.
-是真的吗? -你一定要看看我的属害
-You can actually stand on a board? -I'll be back.
-你能站得上生浪板吗? 一珊上回来
You're gonna see what I can do everything's gonna be good...
你会看到我的属害 包君满意
-...and I'm coming with you. -l can't imagine a better day.
-我一定要跟你走 -要是这样那我就出运嗓
Ma! Ma, he came-- the scout. Mikey. He came. He's here.
妈! 星探米基，他来了
-What? Yeah. -He's giving me a shot now, Ma.
-什么? -他要让我试镜
You want to come watch me surf?
你要来看我征浪吗?
-No, that's okay. -Just this time.
-不用啦 -就这一次嘛
-I'm busy. I'm chopping here. -Okay. All right, well, wish me luck.
-我很已，我有急要末 -好，那就祝我好还吧
Cody, just be careful of those big waves.
酷弟，小心那些大浪啊
Well, anytime now.
可以开始了吧 !
You should have been here yesterday. We had a sweet swell yesterday.
你昨天就该来的 昨天的浪很钙
l was doing some layback 360s and floaters. It was insane.
我秀了好绑次水上淋和七龙珠
Wow! Start the whale.
喂，开鲸船吧
No! Wait! Wait! Just give me one more chance.
不，等等，再给我一次机会
-All l need is one, please. -You just had it.
-再一次就好，求来你 -我看通啦
-Dude, please don't go. -Tough break, kid.
-拜旗你别走 -算你个梯
-Just wait one second. -Better luck next year. Move it.
-等一下就好 -明年再说吧，快开
-Let's go. He's coming! -Just one wave. That's alll need.
-快走，他来了 -再等一道浪就好
I've never won anything my whole life.
我这草子没当过第一
Just once I want to feel like a winner.
这次我很想有冠军的感觉
l used to scout songbirds. Toucans for this musical revue in Brazil.
我以前发据歌星 星光帮的歌手都是我找的
Now that's show business. Toucans--
那才是演艺转
Hold on!
等等
I don't care what you say, I'm coming to Pen Gu!
不管说什么我都要去企头岛
No way, no how. This is a contest for big-wave surfers.
下次再说吧 这比赛只有街明大浪的人能参加
Can't this blubber ball go any faster? Step on it, fish sticks!
这个大刍丸不能再开快点吧? 踩油门啊，福州丸
No, no, no, no!
不、不、不
Poor kid. I feel bad a little bit. Honestly, this is embar--
真可民，我匣他准，说真的…
No, wait! Wait!
等等
Did you guys see that? He almost had my board!
看到没? 他差点就上船了
He almost had it. Next time we'll get it.
差点就成功了，再一次就行
-Yeah, so anyway-- -Wait!
-对啦，反正… -等等
We got you. We got you. Oh, you are heavier than you look.
抓住你了，看不出来你那记重陡
-Man, we did it. -Thank you.
-呼，抓到了 -谢谢
Teamwork always pays off.
团结力量大嘛
-I'm Chicken Joe, man. -Thanks, Joe.
-我是焦麻难 -谢牧，焦焦
Don't you ever, ever, do anything like that in the contest, all right?
比赛时绝对不准摘这套，人懂吗?9
-I'm in? -Yeah, you're in.
-我进了? -对
Because that was entertaining, in a horrifying sort of way.
因为越省狗血观因越过看
Right on, dude.
好耶，炊迎
My name's Cody Maverick, Shiverpool. You?
我叫故酶弟，住暖暖，你呢?
No, I'm not from Shiverpool.
我不是暖暖人
-Where are you from? -Dude, I'm from Lake Michigan.
-那你是哪里人? -我家住内湖，我都在那儿和本浪
That's where I surf. ! was the only one...
在我家乡
.. around my town who did it.
只有我会街浪
A lot of people thought Il was crazy, but I'm used to that.
大家都当我是疯子，不过我习惯了
-l know how you feel, Joe. -You do?
-我知道你的感觉 -真的?
-Yeah. -Radical.
-是啊 -有锡狗
-Butt freeze! -Somebody help the chicken.
-已乐屁 ! -来人抓难啊 !
Look out!
一小心 -蓝死人
Slater, Machado. How's it going, bros?
薛凯子、马小九，你们好吗?
-Good. Thanks. -What's up, buddy?
-很好，谢啦 -你吓?
Okay. Later, dudes.
不错，回头见唆
Radical.
有锡狗
Dude, look where I'm standing. I'm standing where Z stood.
快看，我站在乙钟站过的地方
-Aw, man. -Dude, you gotta try this.
-天哪 -酷弟，你一定要吃吃看这个
-No, I'm okay. -Come on. Just one bite.
-不用了 -来嘛，吃一口
All right. One bite, that's it.
好吧，就一口
Yeah, yeah? What do you think?
味道怎榜?
It's not bad. It kind of tastes like chicken--
不错吃，味道吃起来有芍…蕉…
Yep. What's chi-chi?
什么鸡蕉 ?
Coming through! Oh, crap.
借过 ! 吗，讨原
Oh, man. I'm in love.
哇，我伙爱了
Help me! I'm drowning!
救命 ! 我要淹尿了
What are you standing here next to me for? Go talk to her, man.
你还杆在这干嘛 ? 去跟她哈啦啊
-I'm not gonna talk to her. -She's digging on you.
-我才不要和她哈啦 -她笋到你虽
-She called you crap. -Joe.
她说你“讨厥^
-Thanks again. -All right, well...
-又欠一次 -好了
. this is the third time you've been unconscious this week.
这是你这星期第三次得迷了
I just don't think it's very good for your brain.
这样下去脑袋瓜会变策唱
-l know. Bye, Lani. -Okay.
-我知道，拜，蓄妮妮 -没事啦
Yeah, that was awesome how you saved his life and all.
真属害，救了他一命
That was just unbelievable. Really.
你真的很棒，真的
You here for the surf contest?
你是来参加生浪大赛的?
-Well, I'll be watching you. -Really? You'll be watching me?
-我会果著你的 -真的? 人会果著我啊?
Well, yeah, from the lifeguard station.
会啊，和从救生台上
-Yeah. Right. -It's my job.
-对虽 -那是我的工作
-That's your job. -Are you gonna kiss her?
-那是人的工作 -你到底要不要踊她?
-What's going on? -Come on, Joe.
-现在是怎檬? -拜旗，焦焦
-You were saying you were in love-- -No, I didn't say that.
-你刚刚说你本党了 -我没说
-Look, he really digs you. -Joe, listen--
他很哈你，他喜欢和哟
He likes you, though. See you.
他很哈你，他过人哟 竺哈
l love my job. I have an amazing job.
我党我的工作，我的工作很棒
Just this week, with the contest...
这星期有街浪大赛
.it's a little crazy. You really have to be extra, extra attentive.
会忙翻天 我得特别小心才行
When you have so many guys in the water you can't miss a thing.
到时候海里会挤爆，不能大意
But you know what? I have a perfect record. I've never lost anybody.
不过我记录完美，和从未失手
Sure, there have been close calls, but--
用次是很蓝险，不通…
-Help! -Oh, Arnold. I turn my back for one--
-救人喔 ! -阿诺，我才转个身
-Just lay some feeling on her. -How do you mean?
-去对她放电啊 -放什短电啊?
-Through words. Through touch. -Walk me through the approach.
-甜言密语，肢体语言啊 ! -那张避一下
-I'm Lani. You're me. -You sure about that?
-我当划妮妮，你当我 -你确定?
-I get real serious. -Let's not. Let's not.
-我可会来真的唱 -和拜旗别来
-Whoa. -What is it?
一哇 -什么东西?
That's it! That's Big Z's shrine.
那里，那是乙钙纪念碑
-Remember? -No, no. Not really.
-记得吗?9 -不，没印象
Today, the world of surfing lost one of its legends.
今天，和本浪界痛失传奇人物
Big Z took his final ride this morning...
今早就在他和种浪新秀区坦克对决时
..during a competition with up-and-coming surfer Tank Evans.
乙钟生上生前最后一道浪
Z was last seen paddling into a massive swell off Pen Gu Bay.
乙钟的身影消失在企头湾巨浪中
Friends of Big Z gathered to remember and celebrate his life.
亲朋好友规聚一堂悼念歌颂乙钙
What? Hey!
什么?
-Every time. -He's got a pretty good throwing fin.
-百发百中 -他可以到大联盟当投手
Stop doing-- Stop it! Cut it out!
住手，别委了
-That's like three in a row. -Here, give it a shot.
-三达发耶 -来，你也试斌
What? Wait a minute. Look at this.
什么? 等一等，你看看
-Don't. Stop it. -It's a Big Z necklace.
-不要碰，住手 -是乙钙的项急
That's not funny. Stop. Stop! What are you doing?
这不好玩，住手，你干嘛?
Look, everybody, it's Big Z's last fan!
快看， 是乙钙最后一个粉缘
Coming through. Out of the way. Let's go.
借过、让并、走开
-You don't deserve to talk about him. -He's a big zero.
-你不配谈乙钙 -他是大星蜂
-Shut your mouth! -Zero starts with "Z"!
-闭嘴 -曙蜂也有争啦
You'll never be as good as Big Z, Stank.
你永下比不上Z印，鼻坦克
Hey, hey, people, come on now. Smile on your brother.
朋友拜斌，亲成奏计较嘛
-Keep your girlfriend out of this! -You can't do that to my friend.
-叫你妹妹网站去 -你不能欢负我朋友
You're getting quite a workout there. That feels good.
马的不错喔 ! 真舒服
Why don't you work on my glutes a little bit? That's very nice.
乾脆帮我展屁也马一节吧 ? 真爽
-All right. That's enough, guys. -I'll take you on anytime, anywhere.
-好了，镶了 -我随时随地都可以跟你单挑
Well, then how about right here, right now, huh?
那广此时此地如何?
Hey, Mikey, get this kid a board!
米基，玫小鬼拿顽板
All right, who wants to see the little guy take on the champ?
谁想看小九米同大冠军啊?
Little guys rule!
小电米万成 !
A little one-on-one surfing action between Tank Evans and Jerry--
精采的一对一万杀 艾坦克杀手对像瑞…
-Cody. Cody. -Cody Maverick.
-是酷弟 -鹤酷弟
Cody Mavencourt. And the one that rides the biggest wave wins.
对上酷弟麦内裤 和隐上最大浪的人就是赢家
Are you nervous about going against Tank Evans?
对上艾坦克，你会紧张吗?
Ah, Tank. Nervous? What do I have to be nervous about?
罕张? 我有什么好夫张的?
Give it up! Come on, now!
鼓掌，快啊!
I'm gonna chum the water with your head.
我要街得你篇吃尿
-Bring it on, pecker face. Let's go. -Pecker face?
-有种就来吧，央跑饥腮 -尖跑高妥?
It's mine!
-我的浪
So, Cody, when you take your first wave...
当你街上第一道浪，酶弟
..and the whole island's there to watch, what'll it be like?
全国观办都在看，是什么感觉?
It's gonna be amazing. It'll be the best wave of my life.
一定印呆，这会是我此生最棒的浪
I hope the cameras are rolling because you'll want to watch it...
希望你们好好拍，因为大家会想
..over and over and over again. It's gonna be awesome!
一看再看精彩重播 一定酷到爆
I can't look.
我不敢看了
-Poor kid. He's-- Poor kid. -Wow! That was spectacular!
-可情的孩子 -那真是太属了
I'm number one! The Tank!
叫我第一名 ! 扰散坦克 !
We're trying to get the details. The lifeguard just pulled him in.
我们正设法取得最新情况 救生员财把他拉上岸
That's what happens when you take on the Tank, right?
对上坦克，下场就是如此
Cody, Cody!
酷弟，酷弟
-How is he? Okay? What can I do? -Yeah, he's okay.
-他还好吧? 我能做什么吗? -他没事
I can help. Except if there's blood. Just the thought of blood makes me....
我能帮忙，但不能见血 光是想到血就让我…
Somebody help the chicken.
来人救芍啊 !
-Tank, you okay? -Tank needs fuel.
-坦克，你还好吧? -坦克没油了
Mikey, get the board, will you?
米基，拿一下浪板
Come on. Come on. Come on.
快点，醒醒，快啊
-Did I win? I won, huh? -You should've stayed in Antarctica.
-我赢了唉? 我赢了吧? -你该留在老家的
-Oh, wow. -You're gonna be okay.
你不会有事的
Look at that. There's pixies everywhere.
快看，满天都是小星星耶
What do you think about Cody going into a contest and possibly winning?
酷弟参赛，说不定拿冠军的事 你们怎订看?
-You know, I'm-- -Ha.
这个嘛…哈
-Why did you just laugh? -Because he keeps saying "possible."
-你笑什么? -因为他一直说“说不定“
Like it's "possible" that you're gonna win. And you're gonna do anything.
好像你有机会赢一样 好像你会成功
-Really, what are the chances? -They're high. Aren't they high?
-但机率有多少? -很大，胶算很大对吧?
I mean, they're normal chances. It's not like I'm, like, the underdog.
参加就有机会，我又不是三脚工
Hey, Geek! Geek! Get up and help me.
怪脚，起来帮我忙
Geek?
怪脚…
Geek. Wake up! I need your help.
怪妥 醒醒啊 ! 我需要你帮忙
Come on. Get off your lazy butt and come and help me.
快点，勤支你的大屁股，快来帮我
--beautiful dream.
真甜的萝
-Did you ever know Sheila? -No. I don't know Sheila.
-人认识旬嘉零吧?9 -我不认识到嘉堆
-Wait, wait, wait. What? -What?
-等等…堤嘛? 一怎样?
Who's this guy?
这小鬼是谁?
-He's a surfer. He's hurt. -Who are all those guys?
-他是街浪选手，他受伤了 -这些人又是谁?
They're with him. Ignore them.
他们在拍他，别管他们
-Come on. -Lani, what are you doing?
-快点 -蓝妮妮，巡是在干嘛?
If you help him, they'll go away.
只要你救他，他们就会走
-Hey! Get out of here! -Help him!
-给我滚出去 -救他
-Where do you want him? -Nowhere. That's the whole point.
-要我把他丢哪里了? -外面，就把他丢掉
-No outsiders. Come on. -I know, I know, I know.
-不准外人来，拜斌 -我知道，我知道
This is an emergency. He went down bad over the falls. 1 don't know if he--
这是紧急事件 他被浪打尹了，我不知道他…
-And did he hit the reef? -I don't know.
-他撞上珊瑚礁了? -我不知道
I'm not sure. I got him after--
我不确定，反正他就杰台去了…
-What, is he your boyfriend? -No. No.
-他是男朋友? -不，不是
Wait, wait, wait. Looks like he stepped on a fire urchin.
等等，看来他踩到火海及了
Stepped on me? Are you kidding? This guy was dancing on me.
踩到我? 踩到我? 你开玩笑 他根本是在我身上跳舞
Just look at this. Broken, broken, gone, gone, broken, broken, broken....
你看看，断了、断了 订了、订了、断了、断了、断了
This is pretty bad. This is really bad.
情况很，惨缀人赛
-What-- Cody! -I hurt.
-吗1味!好痛! -哦…栈弟
-You're gonna be okay. What? -Maybe I shouldn't have taken that out.
-你不会有事的，怎庆了? -也许我不该把刺拔出来
Poison's released. Wow. Amazing.
再液扩散了，真是神奇
-What's amazing? -That you're still alive.
-什么很神奇9 -你还活著啊
It's all right. I'm gonna fix you up. I can fix your foot just fine.
没关你，我会搞定你和你的脚
-Where is it? I've been looking-- -It's a saw. You just threw a saw.
-跑哪去了 ? 我一直在找你呢 -是句子，你列拔出一把句子
Don't let him move like that. He's pushing the poison all over his body.
别让他乱支 那样会让毒素扩散全身
-Come on, come on. -l know he looks--
-在哪，在哪呢? -他看起来牙然…
Here it is.
找到了
-What are you doing? -What is he doing?
-你想干嘛? -他想干嘛?
This is a sure-fire cure.
万起仙丹
I learned it from an old medicine man. It, well, works wonders.
神医旬伯温教我的 这个…效果可神奇了
-What? No! Not that! -Not what?
-什么?不!别用那招 ! -别用哪招?
What is he gonna-- Gonna what?
他打算要…堤嘛?
-Come on, now. -Geek, stop.
-来吧 -怪脚，别并了
Let's do this. Lani, can you make some water sounds?
开始吧 蓝妮妮，帮忙吐一下好吗?
-Oh, my gosh, this is so gross. -What is water sounds?
-婧呀，你很吐陡 -咕一下什么?
-Come on. Here we go. -No, no, no. You--
-好了，来唆 -不1不!不要
Kid, you better keep your mouth shut. See, what'd I tell you?
你最好闭上嘴 我不是跟你说了吗 ?9
Hold his foot still, Lani. Come on. Knock him out or something.
抓住他的脚，蓝妮妮 乾脆打朝他吧
-I'm running on empty here. -I'm trying!
-我水快放完了 -我在努力了啦
So how you been?
你最近好邑 ?
Wow, sea urchin in the foot. That sounds pretty nasty.
踩到海脆，匠起来担惨的
Yeah.
是啊
How do you cure something like that?
那要怎样治疗呢?
You pee on it.
尿尿在上面
-That's disgusting. -l know!
-好吗嘿 -那还用说
Hey. How long am I stuck with this guy?
这像伙要待在我这里多久?
-Because you know-- -Till he's better.
-撒知道我… -到他复元
Well, come back soon and, please, bring me some clams.
快点回来，拜旗，再带些蛤师来
-No. -I'm running low here.
-不行 -我快没吃的了
I can't keep doing this. You've got to start taking care of yourself.
我不能再这样了，你得照颂自己
-Oh, come on. -Bye.
-拜旗啦 -拜
-Bring me some more clams! -Okay.
-再带些蛤晴给我 -好啦
If it's just as well with you, I don't want to talk about Cody.
可以的话，我不想谈这个酷弟了
He lost. That's it. That's his problem. It's not mine.
他翰了，那是他的问题，不是我的
Aren't you concerned about anybody's well-being--?
你不关心他是死是活?
The kid's fine. He was born in water. He's a penguin, for crying out loud!
那孩子没事，他海生海长 他是企奖，你嘛帮帮忙 !
-Did you see that wave hit him? -That's the whole idea of surfing.
-你看到打到他身上的浪多大吗 ? -这才叫衡浪啊
-l care. I care! -Mikey! Wait till you see this.
-我担心、我在乎 -米基 ! 你们看这个
Look at those little legs. Stick, stick, stick, sticky.
看这人双高仔脚，细死人不偿命
It's the way I walk. I'm constantly--
我走路就是这样
-Boom-chicka-chicka-- -What's with the "boom-chicka-boom"?
-碰恰卡碰… -什么“碰恰卡碰^
I can't stand blood. I can't stand the sight of blood.
我怕看到血 我不能见血
I can't stand... sight of blood. Cody!
我不能…见血，酷弟
-Dude, have you seen my friend Cody? -No.
-老兄，你有看到我脐吉酷弟吗 ? -没
Cody? Cody?
酷弟?
He's not under there.
下面也没有
Cody!
酷弟 !
How's it going, man?
混得怎样啊? 老兄
So l woke up this morning.
我今天早上醒来
I didn't know where I was. It's never a good place to be when you wake up.
不知道自己身在何方 盎起床时总是会有起床气
Come on. Get up.
起来，吃早餐了 太阳曜屁股唆
- don't want to. -Breakfast.
-我不想起来 -吃早餐了
-Wakey, wakey. Come on. - don't want to.
-太阳明尾股唆 -我不想起来
-How's your foot? -My foot--
你的脚还好吧?
-My foot's fine, but my head. -Good. Good. Come on, kid. Get up.
-我的脚很好，可是我的头… -很好，快点，小鬼，起来吧
What the--?
什么味道9
Yeah, I think I got a concussion.
我想我有点脑震温… 咱…哇哩叫
You should meet my brother, Glen. You guys would really hit it off.
你该见见我老哥，你们会很硫吉
Oh, no. No. Where's my necklace? Did you see my necklace? It's gotta--
错糙，我的项鱼呢? 你有看见我的项鱼吗 ?
No, no.
不、不
Big deal. Get yourself another one at Reggie's trinket shops.
又怎样 去雷大克便利店再买一条就好
It's not just some necklace, guy. He gave it to me himself.
那不是普通项鳞，那是他送我的
-Who? -Big Z. When he came to Shiverpool.
-谁? -乙钟，他来暖暖的时候送我的
That guy believed in me when no one else did.
全世界只有他相信我
He told me never to give up and to find a way...
他叫我别放款，找到出路
-...because that's what winners do. -What winners do. Yeah.
-人这样才能当第一名 -还第一名呈，欧了
It's funny, you know, what a loser I became.
粮的是，我变成倒数第一名
Who cares what Big Z said? You got to...
谁管乙捉说什么，你得…
-... you know, do things your own way. -l don't have a way.
-你得走出你自己的路 -我没路可走啊
You do now. Just follow this. It'll take you back to North Beach.
现在你有了“，走这休吧 这休路能带你回北湾
Okay, nice to meet you. Good luck.
很高内认识你，祝你好到
I can't show my face on the beach. I can't go home.
我没脸去海浴，也不能回家
You always visualize where you're gonna be, what you're gonna do.
我们都会想像未来有多匀黄腾达
This ain't it.
不是这步田地
-What are you doing here? -Here.
-你在这里干嘛? -拿去
-Oh, man. Thank you, man. This-- -Yeah.
天哪，谢谢你
That's cool of you to come back.
你又回来真好，谢谢你
-Thank you. -Better keep that knot tight.
你最好绑紧一点
You lose it during a contest, it's a goner.
比赛时要是弄和于，就没了
Yeah, well, I'm not going in any surf contests.
我不会再参加任何生浪比赛了
Well, there's more to surfing than beating Tank Evans, you know.
玩稳浪又不是为了打败艾坦克
Yeah.
唉!
Look at that. You know what you're sitting on there?
你知道你屁股上坐的是什么吗?
That's koa wood.
那是相思村
Best surfboards in the world are made of that stuff.
相思榭能做出最顶级的生浪板
-Yeah? -You got a koa board?
-是吗? -你有相思木的生浪板吗 ?
-No, I don't have a "board" board. -Well, you wanna...?
-我速整板都没有 -你要不要…
You want to make one?
要不要做一个?
-Nah. -What?
-不了 -什么?
I come all the way back here to give you the necklace...
我大老速跑来拿项鳞给你
..and I'm offering to make you a board and you say, "Nah."
还提议帮你做浪板，你名说不想
Get off your lazy butt. We're making a board. Come on.
给我动起来，我们要做衡浪板了
-All right. -It's gonna be the best board...
这会是你这草子
..you ever had.
最棒的浪板
-All right? -Okay, man.
-好吗? -好啦
Cody!
酷弟
That's cool.
酷啊
Joe, can you just tell us why you're out here looking for Cody?
说说你为什么跑出来找酷弟?
You know, we've known each other way back...
我们很久以前就认识
.. since, like, yesterday, I think it was. We got a lot in common.
从昨天开始，我想是的 我们有很多地方很像
! never really knew my father either.
我也不大认得我老爷
Why are you making surfboards in the middle of the jungle anyway?
我们干嘛在闵林里做生浪板?
I'm just trying to understand. I don't get it.
我只是想搞清楚，我真的…不了
Forget the 20 questions. Let's just get the board made.
省掉那些快问快答 来做生浪板吧
Okay, it's just-- Are you a surfer, or do you--?
好吧， 只是… 你是生浪手吗? 还是你…
Why are we pushing it? Why don't we just roll it?
干嘛用推的? 干嘛不用滚的?
I'm sorry. I didn't mean--
对不起，我不是故意的
I didn't know your foot was there. Are you okay? I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
我不知道你脚在那里， 还好吧? 歹势
It's not like I intentionally did it. I'm sorry.
我不是故意的，和对不起
-Cody. The log! -Yeah, I know!
-酷弟，木头 -我知道啦
Geek! Stop, stop!
怪脚，停、停!
Cody, grab the vine. Grab the vine!
抓住芒蔓、抓住肪蔓
-Now, pull it. -I'm trying!
-用力拉 -我在用力啊
Pull!
拉啊!
Cody!
酷弟 !
Geek!
怪脚 !
Oh, no, no, no.
虽上不，不，不，不
Help me up so I can kick your butt.
拉我上去，好让我扇你一顿
-l thought I killed you. You okay? -Next time, when I say don't roll the--
-我以为我客死你了，你没事吧? -下回我说不要滚的时候…
Wait. What's that?
等等，那是什么 ?
Yeah, it's a beach. Sand, water, sun.
是啊! 是个海江 沙滩、水、吧光
You seen one, you seen them all. Let's get out of here.
全都一榜，没啥好看的，走吧
No, come on, man. Let's go check it out.
我们去看看嘛
You think Cody and the Geek are doing all right?
你想酷弟和怪脚合得来吗?
Yeah. I hate to see him living out there all alone.
会吧，我不忍心看他当独居老人
It'll be good for him to have something to do.
让他有点事做也好
Hey. Somebody's old board shack.
嘿，有间征浪小屋
Look at this.
你看看
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
味1哇1!哇!
These are Big Z's boards.
这些是乙钙的街浪板
Yeah, these are Big Z's boards. He rode this in the Australian Open.
他在澳洲公开赛用过这瑰
This is the board he rode when he came to Shiverpool, man.
他来暖暖用的就是这圳
This-- I-- Geek!
这…我…怪歼 !
This is Big Z's place, man! This is where he lived!
这是乙钙的木屋 他住过这多 !
This is where he made his boards!
他在这里做浪板 !
Did you know this was here?
你知道这里吗? 你为什么不想下来这里?
And then he went up to this old shack, you know.
接著他走向这间痰木屋
And I realized, you know...
我突然明白
it was Z.
他就是乙钙
I could tell he needed some space and some time to himself.
我明白他需要一个人静一静
I didn't want to ask him all these questions.
我不想问他一些有的没有的
So I just kind of stood there quietly.
所以我站在一私…冷静下来
You're Big Z! I can't believe it.
你就是乙钙 ! 我真不敢相信
You're alive! You're alive!
你逮活著 !
That's the respectful way to go, I think.
我想那是一种尊重
Why are you alive? What happened?
你怎订膛活著 ? 怎么回事?
Tell me everything. Start at the beginning and just go.
快告诉我，话说从头你就开始吧
Kid! You're gonna hurt yourself. Relax.
小子，你会伤到自己的，别激动
And people said you were dead, but you're not dead. You're in hiding.
大家都说你死了 你没死，你租起来了
Did something happen? Something happened.
发生什么事? 一定有
You saw something you weren't supposed to see.
你看到什么你不该看的
I knew it! That's what happened!
我就知道，就是这样
Are you nuts? It's not a conspiracy. It's no big deal.
你瘦啦 ? 摘除谋论，没那样啦
-What happened? -l don't want to talk about it.
-到底怎大了? -我不想谈
You don't-- Okay, I got it!
你不想…我懂了
I'll be over here if you need anything or you just feel like talking.
我在这等著，等你想谈再说
Do you feel it now? Like talking now?
现在你有感觉了? 想谈了?
-Go away. -Got it. All right. I'm going away.
-走开 -收到，好，我走开了
Unless you--
除非你…
-Cody! -Okay, got it.
-酷弟 -好，我懂啦
I'm not gonna lie to you. This is, like, it's huge, man.
我不蔓你，这件事真的很大人条
It changes everything. The contest is a few days away.
这改释了一切 比赛通儿天就要天始了
If l can get him to train me, then-- Boom. I could win this with him.
要是我能让他训我 有了他我就能赢得比赛
It's my dream. And I don't want to give up on that dream.
这是我的梦想，我不想放球
Winners find a way, no matter what, right?
要当第一名就要找到出路
A winner is....
第一名是…
They see their goals. They just go for it.
他们设定目标，人坚持下去 他们不是为了袋或面子比赛
-A winner is...like.... -Hey, hey!
第一名就像…
It's the surfer who's out there having the most fun.
就是海上玩得最乐的生浪手
Yep, it's a lot of fun.
是啊，真的很殉
Right, I get you. What's winning without the losers?
如果没但 第一名怎庆会丈?
They're in it for the joy of it and the rapture...
他们为了生浪的乐趣而参赛
..and the slow-motion instant replay, which is my--
还有立即慢支作重播
Head over to the snack bar and get yourself a big bowl of shut up!
去拿点心塞住你的高跑吧 !
Feels better when there's a lot of losers around.
看到越多手下败将我就越更
Was that your question?
你问的是这个吗?
A winner is somebody who doesn't knock me off my surfboard...
真正的第一名不会把我撞下浪板
..and break it when I'm trying to get some big waves.
在我衔大浪的时候玉事
Especially Tank. He is definitely not a winner.
特别是坦克，他才不是第一名
He's a dirty trashcan full of poop.
他是一肚子“赛”的尿人
Yeah, I can't remember a time when I wasn't surfing.
我打从娘胎就一直在生浪
My mom put me right on there. I think she pooped me out...
是我妈把我放上去的 我想她把我生出来
.. Just put me right on there.
就直接放上浪板
What is it about surfing that you love?
你喜数生浪哪一点 ?
I love being the center of attention...
我喜欢成为目光焦点
. . because it's really where I should be.
因为我天生就是大明星
And I love the looks my ladies give me, you know?
我还喜欢我的美眉们看我的样子
The little glint. I love that. I love holding the ladies.
浆内发光，迷死人 我喜欢抱著美居
-You know what I'm talking about? -I think so.
-你懂我的意思吗? -应该懂吧
-Sort of. -Come with me.
-大概懂 -跟我来
Put this curtain in myself.
帘子是我自己装的
These are my ladies.
这些就是我的美居
This is Jill. This is my lady, Amy.
这是小雪 这是铃木亚美
Little Suzie. Briana.
小苏西、眉昂西
-You know why we call her Briana? -No.
-知道她为什么叫碧兄西吗? -不知
It's a long story.
说来话长
Shaniqua. Helga. Miss Kitty.
大种党、松浦吗恋、演亚步
Jeannie. I dream of....
布将妮，我的小甜甜
Theresa. This is Theresa right here.
隋党 这个我叫她隋党
-Now, is Theresa, is that your-- -Dirty girl.
-那隋党是你的… -性感女神
This spot? This spot is for my special lady, Lia.
-这个位子? -这是留给我最特别的莉亚
I'm gonna say that one more time. Lia. Oh, yeah.
我要再说一次 痢亚，好陡
That's a sweet, sweet lady.
我的心肝小宝中
Tank! Are you polishing your trophies again?
坦克 ! 你又在摸你的宝贝了?
Mom, I wasn't polishing. l was talking to my friends.
妈，我没有摸，我在跟朋友聊天
I'm gonna be polishing later.
我等一下再摸
When's he coming out? I'm running out of film.
他什么时候出来? 底月快没了
Mr. Topanga! Could you tell us why you're not dead?
乙印，能不能说说你怎庆没死?
No! lam dead! I'm dead.
不能，我是死了
What are you doing?
你在干嘛?
Hey, who said you--
谁说你可以…
Turn the board around. Get back here.
动我的浪板，给我回来
Come out here and show me some moves.
快来海上教我冯招
-No, no. -Come on!
-不要 -来嘛
-Grab a board and come out. -You want to kill yourself, go ahead.
-快拿塌板子，出来啊 -你想玩命，请便
Fine with me. Just don't mess up my board.
我无所谓，别弄玉我的板子就好
-How do you turn this thing? -It's not a short board. Sit back on it.
-那不是短板，往和后坐
Hey, watch the wave!
小心海浪
You mess up my board, I'm messing up your other foot.
你敢和弄壤我的板子 我就打断你另一焦脚
I'm just trying to ride this canoe or whatever it is, okay?
我只想玩一下这艘像木徐的东东
Stop trying so hard! Just relax.
别玩的那订辛苦，放到疾
What do you mean, rela--?
怎夭样放轻…
Long, smooth strokes.
长划水
-Dig deep. Dig, come on. -I'm digging!
-划深一点，划啊 -我在划，我在划
Keep the nose up! Keep it up! Watch it! You're pearling!
板头抬高，小心，你吃水了
-What are you doing? -Come on, please?
-你在要什么实 ? -拜旗啦
Z, l can't learn anything with you on the beach.
你桂在沙滩上我根本学不到东西
Well, then you're not gonna learn anything.
那你就什么也学不到了
-Now, come on in. -I'm not coming in until you come out.
-上来吧 -我不上去 ' 除非你下海
Oh, you're coming in, all right. He's not even watching the wave.
你会回来的 他根本没在看浪
-What wave? -That one.
-什亡浪 -那一道浪
Five, four, three, two, and....
五、四、三、二…
-Don't touch my stuff, man. -l couldn't help it.
-别乱碰我的东西 -我忍不住
-I just wanted to learn from the best. -Yeah, well.
我想得到高手的真传
-l don't surf anymore, okay? -What?
-我不生浪了 -什么?
What do you mean, you don't surf?
什么叫你不生浪了?
You want to learn how to surf the right way?
你想学会真正的生浪吗 ?
Then you gotta make your own board, all right?
那你得动手做自己的浪板
-What do you mean, you don't sur-- -Can't hear you.
-什么叫你不生浪… -区不到
-Can I ask one question-- -We're making a board.
-我能不能阅个问题 -我们要做浪板
Could you tell me about your board?
能不能谈谈你的街浪板?
I just have a palm tree board.
我只有棕栏顶浪板
I would have to say it's not the nicest board in the world...
我想说它不是世界第一等的浪板
..but it is a pretty good board.
不过还不错用唱
The ancient Hawaiians believe that "mana" or heart...
十时夏威夷人相信在做浪板时
..Was transferred into the surfboard as you shaped it.
你的精神也会融入板中
What are your thoughts on that?
你相信这个说法吗?
What's up with the hair? You could fit a whole fish in there.
你头毛怎么了 ? 里面可状焦羊了
My dream surfboard. It's pretty powerful.
我的欧幻浪板，要火力强大
You can add a lot of attachments to it, like a grenade launcher attachment.
可以在上面加装很多武器 像反坦克手榴弹
Anybody know whose board this is?
有人知道这是谁的板子吧?
-I'm pretty sure it's the chicken's. -Has anybody seen the chicken?
-针定是那焦获的 -有人看到那焦鸡吗?
Cody!
酷弟 !
I know he's out here. Il can feel it in my nuggets.
我知道他在这，我有灼六感
Aren't you nervous out here in the jungle? It's kind of dangerous.
你在莱林里不会怕吗 ? 有点危险
Dude, the jungle is the most peaceful place on the planet.
安啦，娄林是世上最安全的地方
-Hold it steady. -This is a dream come true.
-折稳了 -我实现欧想了
This is a dream come true, to be here with Z, doing this.
美劳成真，在这和乙钟做浪板
-And it's koa wood. -Where's the--
还是相思顶
All the best boards are made from koa wood.
最棒的生浪板都是相思枚做的
All right, now, I drew this pattern as a guide.
好了，我先书出板形当参考
Do you want to have your board with a lot of rocker or just a little?
你的浪板弧度要大一点还是小?
I don't know.
我不知道
What you want is something in-between. Trust me.
你要的是介於中间的缴度，相信我
-I'm the expert here. -Okay.
-我是专家 -好吧
So...
这是你的雕刻刀
Now, remember, the board's already inside there, see, somewhere.
记住，浪板已经在里面某个地方
And what you're doing is you're trying to find it.
而你要做的是，把它发据出来
-Reveal it. All right? -Okay.
-解放它，好唉? -好
Every carve counts. Why are you smiling? Don't smile.
每一划都很重要 你在笑什么?不要笑
-I'm not smiling. I'm excited. -This isn't like hacking a piece of ice.
-我没有笑，我是很机竺 -这可不像创冰并
It takes patience and finesse.
这需要耐性和技巧
All right already. Can you just give me the tools, please?
好啦，快把工具给我，好吧?
-Here, take it. Go ahead. -Thank you.
-拿去吧，拿去 -谢谢
-Here we go. -What are you doing?
-开工吗 -你在干嘛?
If you're gonna do it, do it right.
你要做就要做的对
All right, look. First of all, with the grain.
看著，首先要顺著纹路齐
With the grain. You see what I'm doing here?
顺著纹路，你看见没?
You let the tool do the work. You see?
让工具来做工
Just like you're riding a wave. You let the wave do the work.
就像你街浪时，让海浪来做工
You don't fight the wave. You can't fight these big waves.
你不抗拒海浪，大浪扰法抵抗
Long strokes. Loads of finesse.
滑通去，要很有技巧
Find the board within the tree.
发据顶干里的生浪板
-Nice and easy. -Yeah, I got it.
-潭然天成 -好，我上
See that? You just...
看到没? 就路…
-You just... -Maybe I could do it now.
一芷… -也许可以让我来了
Move with...
顺著…
-With the... -Can I do it now?
-顺著… 一输到我了吗?
Can I do it now?
输到我了吗?
Yeah. I got carried away. Sorry about that.
我太沉迷了，不好意思
-It's your board. -My board.
-这是你的板子 -我的板子
Okay, with the grain. I got it.
-顺著纹路剂，我懂 -别忘了偶关要端详一下
-Long strokes, with the grain. -Not too long.
-滑过去，顺著纹路 -别滑太下了
Here we go.
开始唆
-You're doing it wrong. -Will you just let me--
-你方法全错 -拜旗你让我…
I can't-- No finesse when you're in my face. Okay?
你桂在这我没法大展身手
Just let me make the board.
让我做我的板子吧
-Do you want my help? -No, I don't want your help.
-你要我帮忙吗? -我不要你帮忙
I don't want your help.
拜旗不要帮
-You don't want my help? -[ don't want your help.
-你不要我帮忙 ? -我不要你帮忙
-All right. Fine. -l want to make my board.
-那好啊 -我想做我自己的板子
-Build the board yourself, all right? -Thank you.
-那你就自己做板子吧 -感恩
I don't care what the board looks like. You're the one...
我才不管板子好不好看 反正
-...who's got to ride the thing. -Fine. Thank you.
-要用的人是你 -好，谢谢
-It's in there somewhere. -Walk over there, please! Please.
-浪板就在那里面 -走开一点，拜旗你
Don't cut yourself.
别割到手
So it's day three, yeah?
这是第三天了
I come across Pen Guans.
我遇上了到美族
I'm Chicken Joe. Joseph. It's long for Joe.
我是焦太区，大家都叫我焦焦
Sweet, man.
水唾
And they treat me as their king and put me in a hot tub.
他们把我当国王 还招待我泡汤
It is, 1 guess, their royal hot tub.
我猜是他们的御用SPA
It got kind of hot and steamy.
水好热，蒸所好舒服
It was kind of cool.
让我的从毛孔都打开了 好大，他们让我簿泡澡净吃大餐
It was like dinner and a show.
晚餐外加歌甸秀
As enjoyable as it was, I still had a vision of my quest.
路然很享受 我还是记得我的肩负重任
Thank you. See you guys later. I gotta get going.
谢谢，有缘再相会，我得由了
Not again.
又来了
You know what else it was? Il had the board.
你知道后来怎样? 浪板做好了
The board was fine. The board was great.
板子很好、很棒
-How's it going? -It's going great, man. It's great.
-进行的如何? -很棒，很读
It did look a little rough.
看起来是有点避
A little rough? The board looked a little-- It's a work in progress, bro.
有点膛? 看起来有点… 这还是半成品
You think it's good enough for the big waves?
你想它足以抵抽大浪吗?
I think it's good enough for any wave.
我想什么浪都难不合它
Hang on.
等等
-Okay, let's say I'm a big wave. -Hold on. No, no, no, no.
-好，就当我是大浪好了 -等等，不要
-Hey, where you-- -Hold on!
-你这是… -等等
-Where are you going? -It's my board, man, all right?
-你要去哪? -这是我的板子
Why don't you take your board and go try it out?
你何不拿著你的板子下海试试?
Maybe I will. Piece of junk. Watch!
试就试，垃圾肥，看好了
Nice ride, man. Nice ride.
钟喔，小撮 有劲哩
This is supposed to be fun.
生浪是要乐在其中
I got three days until the contest. I don't have time for fun.
我还有三天就要比赛了 我没时间玩乐
No time for fun, huh?
没时间玩乐，是喔?
-Hey, Cody! -What?
-酷弟 一怎样?
Bring me some clams when you come back!
回来时带点蛤晴给我
I'm not coming back!
我不回来了
-He'll be back. -No, I won't!
-他会回来的 -我才不会
He'll be back.
他会回来的
-You guys like barbecue? -Yeah, sure.
-你们训欢烤肉吗? -喜驳
Got some wood here.
这壬有木妆
Il wasted my whole day and I have nothing to show for it, which is--
我浪费了一整天分毫扰进展
-l was just going to check on you... -That's why you were--
-我正要去看看你和…， -所以娩才…
..and the Geek.
怪妥
-Listen. The Geek is Big Z. -What?
聘我说，怪脚就是乙钟
-l know. -You know?
我知道
-How did you find out? -We went to the beach.
-你是怎庆发现的? -我们去了海江
-You got him to the beach? -Yeah.
你把他拉去海光 ?
I've been trying to get Z out of that tree for 10 years...
我花了十年都没把他拖出顶屋
..and you got him all the way down to the beach in one day?
你一天就让他一路跑去海湾 ?
This is fantastic!
这真是不得了
It's amazing! Do you want to go somewhere fun?
太属害了 想不想去个好玩的地方?
Do you want to go somewhere really, really fun?
想不想去个超级有乐子的地方?
Unless you want-- Did you want to get back to Big Z?
除非你…你要回去找乙印?
-I'm sorry. l shouldn't have invited you. -No, no, no.
-对不起，我不该洲你的 -什么? 真的，不用?
-What? Okay. No? -No, look. 1 want to have fun.
-我想找乐子 -好
-Okay. -Do I need mints or something?
-我要不要先刷牙?
-You tell me. -No, you won't need mints.
一虹说呢 -不用刷牙啦
Z used to carry us up here on his shoulders. We'd have so much fun.
我以前常坐在乙名肩膀上来这 每区来都好开心
-It's one of my favorite spots. -Really?
-这是企头岛上我最喜欢的地方 -真的?
-Boy, to be 8 years old again. -What is this?
-好像回到八茂的时候 -这用来干嘛?
You don't want to get all cut up, do you?
你不会想弄得全身是伤吧
Hold on. What are you doing?
等等，你干嘛? 我要走了， 我要浆…
It's going down! No, no, no!
我掉下去了…不… !
-This is insane! -Stop fighting it, Cody! Just let go!
-太恐怖了 ! -别抗抱，酷弟，放手玩
Now I'm in front of you. What's going on now?
我生到人前面了 现在怎庆样啊?
It's not a race!
这又不是比赛
Okay, wait, don't take the left-- Cody!
等等，别往左下…
-Give up, slowpoke! It's over with now! -Not for long!
-放素吧，小岛龟，人坦了 -你赢不久的
Give up now, sucker!
放计吧，三脚工
-l beat you! -Congratulations, you sure did.
-我赢了 -茶喜你，你是赢了
You should probably get out of there.
你最好赶快起来
Why is that? This stuff is-- Look at me. It's so beautiful.
为什么? 你看，这好美
Look at it. What is this stuff?
你看，这是什么 ?
See those things up above you? They're glowworms.
看到上面那些没? 是莹火业
So you're right beneath them. Yeah, that's poop.
你正好在它们下方的… 便便池里
You know how some stinks stink and other stinks smell good?
有些臭味很臭，有些和臭得很香
-Yeah. -This is, like, a good stink.
这种臭味就很香
A good stink?
臭得很得?
Can I tell you something personal?
我能跟你说业私事吗?
We're in the shower together. You can say whatever you want.
澡都一起洗 了，想说什条都可以
I'm serious. I'm really, really jealous of you.
我是说真的 我真的真的真的很忌妒你
Why?
为什么 ?
I couldn't get Z off his butt for the last 10 years...
我十年来都无法让乙钙出门
..and then you come along and....
而你一来就…
He must really think a lot of you.
他一定很看重你
I don't know. I've been a jerk to him. I don't know what he thinks.
我不知道，我对他态度很烛 我不知道他怎麻想
-You haven't. -I have. I've been a jerk.
-不会啦 -我有，我对他很壤
-l have. -Then go not be a jerk.
-真的 -那就别…对他很壤
What does it matter to you anyways?
你又是为了什么这废关心他?
He's my uncle. He's the only family I've got.
他是我鼻血，是我唯一的亲人
Okay.
好员
Z? No.
乙钟?不要
-No. -Let's see here.
-不要 -我们来看看
-l swear... -It's stronger than I thought.
-我发扑… -我看看，它比我想的要坚固
-...if you break it-- -Should've been broken by now.
-要是你弄断它 -要断早该断了
Come on! Come on!
拜斌，别并了
Look at that.
你看那个
That's the best place in the world to be, in the tube.
天下最议的地方在那里 海浪隧道
Really?
真的?
Yeah. Better than winning, the trophy, all that stuff.
是啊，比得第一名拿金牌还更
Tube riding is the ultimate thing in surfing...
隧道生浪是生浪的终极享受
...to ride inside the wave and make it out of it
生进浪里，全身而退
It's all we want to do every day.
这是我们每天可浪的梦幻动作
It's almost impossible to describe.
其中滋味无可言喻
There's nothing ! can compare it to.
没有比它更讲的事了
It's a feeling that not too many people will experience...
这种经验很少人有
...80 it's special in that sense.
因此它也很特别
Then you try to remember it.
接著你会念念不忘
Like, "I wish I could remember that," or "l wish I could get that again.
你会想回味，想再来一次
It's so addicting.
真的会上净
Once you get inside you never want to get out.
你一衡进去，就再也不想出来了
-Wow. That's amazing. -Yeah, man. Nothing like it.
-真是不可思议 -是啊，没什么比得上它
So, that aside, how many points would you get for getting tubed?
拖开那个不谈 隧道生浪能多得疙分?
Like, what does it depend on for the contest?
评审给分的标准是什么?
-Points? -What?
分数?
You know who you sound like right now?
你知道你现在的口气像谁吗 ?
I promote happiness!
我推销快乐
Can you see the happiness emanating from me? What's wrong with you?
你看不出我散发著快乐吗? 你哪根筋不对啊?
-We're live. -Good. Good.
-这是现场播出 -好，好
I have to say, I have no doubt that this year's Big Z Memorial...
毫无疑问，今年的“乙钟街浪祭“
.. 18 gonna be the best ever.
会是有史以来最精彩的
With the competition just one day away...
疮比赛只剩一天
...the excitement is definitely building here on Pen Gu Island.
企头岛的气氛简直爆到最高点
That didn't take too long. I feel lightheaded.
很快就完工了嘛，我有点贫血
So get this.
跟你说虽
On my search for Cody, l bump into my hot tub buddies again.
在找酷弟的路上 我又碰上了我的泡汤朋友
I get it. You guys look hungry.
我了，你们看起来很饿
You've probably got the munchies or something.
你们可能是想吃昧心了
Squidito on el stickito?
小米酒花枝仔烧的啦?
Check it out! Dude, have you seen my friend Cody?
杀哩 ! 你有看到我脐吉酷弟吗?
He's kind of like a penguin.
他长得有点像企躺
He's got a lot of black on him, a lot of white.
背面岛漆抹黑，正面白嘛嘛
-How did you learn how to surf? -l saw Big Z do it, actually.
-你怎么学会衡浪的? -我看乙钟街浪学会的
! don't think you were born yet.
你那时膛没出生吧
-l wasn't? -No, I don't think so.
-还没吗? -我想还没有
Lani? I like her when she teaches us because--
蓝妮妮 我喜欢她教我们，因为…
Smudge! Not another one!
小县灶，你又来了
I think he really has to go to the bathroom right now.
我想他得马上去而所了
What's next? The board is done.
接下来呢? 板子做好了
-The board is done? -The board is done.
-板子做好了? -做好了
-Well, let's do some training. -Finally!
-那就来点训针吧 -等好久了!
-Can we get a shot of you-- -You've got to get it in a long shot.
-我们能不能拍你… -你一定要用长镜头拍
Hey, Z! Come on!
乙钟，快点
-Where you going? -l thought we were going to train.
-你要去哪? -我以为我们要做训练
Not in the water. Jeez. What are you thinking?
不是在水里，你在想什么 ?
-You want to surf like Big Z used to? -Yeah.
-你想跟乙钟一样生浪对吧 ? -对
I've got some tests here to figure out your potential.
我准备了些测验来测试你的洒力
-Let's do it. -No, put them on your eyes.
-开始吧 -不对，要放你的限睛上
-Like this. -On my eyes.
-像这料 -放眼睛上
-Take it, Cody. -Can we do some training, seriously?
-拿去吧，酷弟 -我们能不能做点正经的训练?
What are you talking about? What do you think we're doing?
什么? 那你以为我们在堤嘛?
Acting like nutjobs. That's what I think we're doing.
我党得我们在要白病，就是这样
Yeah, good. You're learning!
很好， 你学隐明了
And a big set comes in.
大浪来唆
Wipeout!
牌爆 !
-That's it! -Take it easy!
-金了! -帮玛朋嘛
This is getting ridiculous.
这太瞎了
-You having fun? -l hate you.
-好玩吗? -我恨你
Big, you know, slow:
遇大浪就慢
He does this flip over the top. All right, now you go.
他在上面翻筋斗，现在换你了
No joy, man. No joy. Fail.
不好玩，不好玩，零分
I'm starting to see it, man. I think I know what you're talking about.
我抓住那个感觉了 我知道你的意思了
That's great. As long as we're all having fun, right?
很正点咏 ! 那不就很好玩是吧?
Z, wake up. Wake up, Z. Z!
醒醒、醒醒啊
Hey, Z, breakfast!
乙钟，吃早餐了
Not a chance.
你想得美
-Four, three, two... -You gotta get up early in the morning--
你得时一点起床才行
.one.
一
That is fun.
这才叫好玩
-You're having fun? -lam. Yes. Now lam.
-你觉得好玩吗? -是啊，好好玩 !
Then, Cody...
那麻，酷弟
-... you passed! -What?
-你过关了 ! -什么?
You did it! You're ready! Let's surf!
你闽人备好了 ! 来街浪吧 !
Don't play me, Z. We're surfing? Yes! Yes!
别要我了，街浪? 好耶!
Hey, check it--
看我的
I didn't know you could surf!
我不知道你还能街浪耶
Relax!
放玛弓
Long, slow, smooth.
长划、慢慢滑、顺著走
-Like making the board! -There you go.
-就像做浪板一样 -说得好
-All right. Okay. -Feels good, yeah?
-好耶 -感觉很爽吧?
-You're in the water, Z! -Come on out. Get wet! Come on!
-乙捉，你竟然下水了 -快来，快点下海来 !
Lani, thank you.
蓝妮妮，谢谢
Look at that!
你看
-Nice! That's it! Nice. -Great ride!
-证吗，就是这样 -干的好 !
Big Z is back!
乙钟回来了
This is what it's all about.
这才叫做本浪啊
What could be better than this?
还有什么比得上这一切呢
1 need some help on this landing for the high note
烦懂爱悉全抛关只要强上一曲 快帮我唱，蓝妮妮唱高音
Nice. Nice.
好耶，好慎
-ls that the only song that you know? -Pretty much.
-你只会唱那首歌吗? -差不多啦
You want to hear it again? It goes like this.
想再史一次吗?9 是这样唱的…
No? Okay. I got you there, didn't I?
不要? 好吧“，我让你沉醉了吧 ?
l must say you were quite amazing out there today.
我得说你今天街浪真的很神
-You weren't so bad yourself, kiddo. -Thanks to this guy.
-你也不吾啊，小撮 -多谢这像伙
-I just pointed you in a direction. -Question, Z.
-我只是指点了你一下 -乙，我问你
-Change your mind about the song? -No, no, no.
-你改变主意想职歌了? -不、不
Here, it goes something like this--
-我要唱唆 -我想问你
l was wondering if you could come watch me ride tomorrow.
明天能不能来看我街浪
Yeah, yeah. We'll both ride, man.
好啊，我们一起衡浪
The Big Z Memorial. Remember that one?
“乙钙生浪上各”，记得吧?
I know I'm asking a lot...
我知道我要求太多
..but it would really, really be...
不过如果你能来 对我来说真的意义非凡
-You still want to be a part of that? -Absolutely.
-你还是想参加比赛?
-Why do you want me there anyway? -l thought you'd want to be there.
-为什么要我去? -我想你会想去
-l don't know why it's a big deal. -It's no big deal.
-我不觉得有什入 -那是没什夭
Why won't you come?
那你为什么不去?
-I'm not coming. -Why?
-我不去 -为什么 ?
-Give it a rest. -It's getting cold, guys.
-不要上钼了啦 -海鲜要泳了
-Tell me why you're hiding. -Hiding?
-你为什么躲起来 ? -躲?
-Why are you hiding? -I'll have to eat all this by myself.
-你在躲什么啊? -我要把海鲜吃光唆
Why didn't you come back after you fell off the wave?
你那次摔浪之和后为什么不回来?
That wave.
那道浪
That last day, winning had become everything to me.
在那一天 赢变成我最重要的一切
1 knew I was gonna beat Tank.
我只知道我会打败坦克
But then, you know, he starts to surf circles around me.
不过和后来 他把我生的转围转
! saw what he was doing. ! couldn't do what he was doing.
我看到他的技巧，但我印学不来
Times had changed.
时代已经贮了
! didn't want to walk back on that beach with all my fans there.
我无颜面对江东父老粉缘
A loser. Everyone looking at Big Z, the loser, the has-been.
我输了，大家会笑乙钙 膛脚，过气
So...
所以
Big Z's dead, and that's how it's gonna stay.
乙钟已死，也不会再复活
Let me play you that song.
我弹那首歌给你隐
What about "never give up"? What about "find a way"?
那广永不放于? 找自己的出路呢?
-You're giving up. You're giving up! -Yeah, I'm giving up. That's my way.
-你估放素了，你放素了 -对，我放于了，那是我选择的路
-Giving up. -l thought you were the one guy.
-放球 -看我还把你当偶像
You don't like it, find your own way.
你不喜获就去走自己的路
Leave me out of it.
不要拖我下水
I messed up. I'm just--
我出包了
I'm...not good.
是我不好
This is when I needed someone. I needed him.
我现在很需要他
It's hard enough losing one dad, but....
失去一个爸爸已经金惨了
-What do you mean by--? -Nothing.
-你的意思是… -没什么
Nothing, man. Forget it.
没什么，当我没说
Peaceful. Peaceful. I'm in peace. I come in peace.
和平和平，我没有显襄
-Cody! -Joe!
-酷弟 ! -焦焦!
-I've been looking everywhere for you! -You've been looking for me?
-我到处在找你耶 -你一直在找我?
I didn't lose you on the whale. I'm not gonna lose you now.
我在急丸船上票你，现在也是
-Thank you. Seriously, thank you. -Radical.
-感轧，好感动，谢谢 -有锡狗
They're starting! Cody, we gotta go! Come on!
比赛开始了，我们得走了
Wait a minute. Joe?
等一等，焦焦?
Surfers riding....
焦焦?
I'm sorry. Watch this, dude. Il can speak their language.
歹势，没问题，我会说他们的话
I totally need my board. I don't know where it is. gotta go find it.
我需要浪板，但我不知道它在哪 我得去找板子
-I'll see you in the lineup. -See you, Joe.
-在会场碰头吧 -回头见，焦
-This is gonna be fun, huh? -See you.
-一定会很好玩的 -回见
The tenth annual Big Z is about to get underway...
第十届“乙钙街浪祭”即将开始
..and, whoa, it is the day of days.
今天真是个超级大日子
Big mountainous bombs marching into our coastline.
扎浪可说是排山倒海迎面而来
Kelly Slater, on a danger level, one to ten, give me a number.
凯子，就危险程度 工到1工 0 给个分数吧
-Wow. Rob? -There'll be blood.
-小九呢? -看来会有血光之党
I'm scared, and I'm in the booth!
我在棚内看了都怕
-What are you doing here? -Mike.
-你在这里干嘛? -米基
You're gonna kill yourself. Don't do this to yourself.
你会送命的，别人这样
Look what happened last time.
看上次出了什么事
-It's good to see you back. -Are you serious?
-很高导看到你回来 -你是认真的?
You're gonna be a real crowd pleaser.
你一定会成为人气王
I'm telling you, these people are gonna eat you up.
我敢说，观办会乐牌的
-I'll be expecting big things from you. -Thank you.
-我期待你精彩的演出 -谢谢
People, big announcement. Cody Maverick, he's back.
各位，大号外，难酷弟回来了
The Wipeout King is back...
牌爆王回来了
..and I'm gonna tell you, start looking for the sharks.
各位，小心车急吧
They'll be circling because there's gonna be blood.
它们等选手见血就会并香而来
Spectacular carnage today.
今天画面保证血腥
Thank you! Reggie Belafonte. Little guy, big hair, big thoughts, big heart.
谢谢 ! 我是雷大克， 脚立地、桶顶天、头好好、心壮壮
Look at this. You're going down, snowflake.
看著吧，你死定了，林人裳玉
I'm gonna make you wish you were never even hatched.
到时你会希望你爸没把你孵出来
You want to see my trophies?
你想看我的奖鼻吗?
Arnold, no.
阿诺，不行
About 24 surfers battling their way out to the--
2 4位选手拼的你死我活
Good golly! Make that 18.
我的妈呀 ! 这下剩1 8个了
Rob, after such a heavy wipeout earlier in the week...
小九，经过之前那次大牌爆
...what do you think is going through Maverick's mind?
你想穴酷弟在想什么?
He's gonna have to stay focused and channel that energy into good places.
他得全和神贯注化悲愤为力量
When are you gonna get a life?
你什么时候才要面对现实?
You are a nobody.
你是个庆物
He made it! Yeah, good.
他成功了，好台
What an amazing first ride mind-blower from Maverick.
故酷弟第一翰表现让人到目相看
Did you guys see that?
你们看到没?
Man. I thought I was gonna lose it, and then I just...
我以为我会摔个稀巴烟
I just let go, you know. I let go, and there it was.
然后我放手轻朋地生，就成功了
Wow, it's been an amazing day...
今天真是高潮选起
...0f shredding in less than stellar conditions...
高手纷纷中稍落马
..but 1 never would have guessed our three finalists.
进入决赛的前三强真是大爆冷门
Well, Sal, it's no surprise that Tank Evans...
毫无意外的，艾坦克
..has just breezed his way into the finals.
他轻轻朋朋就进了决赛
And Cody Maverick, from a horrible wipeout a few days ago to this.
堆酷弟从之前的大牌爆到今天
And Chicken Joe from Sheboygan. Who would have guessed it?
内湖来的焦太区更跌破大家限镜
! have never seen a finals like this.
我从没看过这样的决赛
-We're in the finals, Joe. -No way! We get to surf some more?
-我们进决赛了，焦焦 -真的! 我们可以继续生更多浪?
Isn't it exciting? Look at that. This is great, huh?
很内军吧 ? 你看看，这太棒了
You know, you should know this. The Tank loves you.
你们要知道，坦克爱死你们了
Looks like this will be the easiest year ever.
看来今年会是最耘用的一年
No way. Cody, did you hear that? It's gonna be easy.
不会吧，你匠见没? 会很轻轰耶
Are you loving this?
大家素不卖啊?
So who would you like to see win the trophy?
你们希望谁赢得奖番 ?
It's not so important to me.
这对我来说没那刻重要
Friends are better than anything in the world.
朋友比任何事情都重要
Friends are forever.
朋友是一人昔子的 奖番，又不会陪你一起玩
-That was awesome, mate. -Muy impresivo, my friend.
-干的好，小老弟 -钦胀雷啊 !
Thank you, bro. Thanks.
谢谢你们
-Finals. -Hey!
决赛耶
Yeah. I know. I can't even--
我知道，我没想到…
I think I can win this thing. It's too much right now.
我想我有胶算，但没想到会这度稳
-Well, that's all you came for. -What?
-你已经建到目的 -什么?
-What is that supposed to mean? -You made it pretty clear last night...
-这话什么意思? -你昨晚说得很明白
.. that winning's more important to you than Z or me.
拿第一比乙钟跟我还重要
But, hey, maybe you'll get to take your stupid trophy home.
不过也疾你真能带个策痪番回家
-Lani. Come on. -Come here, you!
-蓝妮妮，别这样 -你，过来
How about this, huh?
聘我说
Let me tell you something. You win this thing, we're going places!
我告诉你 只要你赢，你我就发速了
Look at this kid. He is a champ!
看看这孩子，他是冠军
Tank, nine-time defending champion. He will roll on you.
九度本晃冠军的坦克 他不会手下留情的
Expect him to win this thing. It's basically a contest for second place.
他铁定拿第一，大家只能抢第二
First, I'm gonna take you down. Then I'm gonna fry the chicken.
我先把你绰掉 再来炸申酥难
That cloud looks just like a kitten.
那条去好像凯蒂猫喔 !
Maverick and Evans take off.
酷弟和坦克开战了
Mine!
我的浪 !
And it's Evans dropping in.
坦克和本上浪头了
And Tank's playing games, blocking Maverick's every move.
坦克施技阻找了酷弟的每个动作
Maverick sticks a rail.
酷弟化险为现
Tank Evans down! ! have never, ever seen this before!
坦克落水了
But I'd love to see it again.
不过我很乐意再看一次
Cody trying to take back the wave that Tank snaked from him.
酷弟设法夺回坦克偷走的浪
Evans toying with him, not paying attention.
坦克在要他，一时失察
And there's the outside rail. Evans goes down.
衙浪板失控，坦克落水
And it's Maverick with this new-school move. We'll call it "The Maverick."
堆酷弟展现他的创新花招 我们就叫它“礁来这一招^
And look at this. Maverick scoring big.
快看，栈弟得到高分
Oh, it's so cute. It's got little paws and the whiskers.
真可爱，它有小爪子 还有蛙掺呢
Chicken Joe with a no-paddle drop-in!
焦友难没滑水直接上场
-Here we go! -Nobody needs to help this chicken.
-我来唆 -这集蕉没人揣得住
I'm flying!
哆呼 ! 我习了
Maverick and Joe tied, and no score for Tank Evans? Unbelievable.
堆酷弟和焦厅区僵持不下 艾坦克没得分? 不可思议
Surfers, this is your final wave!
选手们，这是最后一道浪了
-Joe, this is it. This wave wins it. -Yeah, man!
-焦焦，这是决胶浪了 -好耶
This wave is stacking up to be a beautiful tube.
这道浪形成美想的隧道
Maverick should score big on this one!
酷弟应该能拿高分
But wait! Evans drops in.
等等，坦克角了进来
It looks like Evans is gonna take out the chicken.
看来坦克打算干掉焦麻难
What's Maverick doing?
故酷弟在干嘛?
-Go, Joe, go! -Got it! Let's go!
-快生，焦焦 -收到，衡街生 !
! don't believe this. This contest was Maverick's to win.
不会吧，堆酷弟本来赢定了
Now Evans pushing Maverick out of bounds and into The Boneyards.
现在名被坦克遥进九拐十入警
-Tank, look out! -You look out!
-坦克 ， 小心 -你才小心吓
Code!
小酷 !
Z!
乙 上
-Cody, come on. -Z!}
酷弟，快点
Paddle! Come on! Dig! Faster! Come on. Dig!
快划工划快一点 ! 快啊!
Don't dig! Don't dig!
别划工别划了
What?
什么?
Let the wave carry you!
让海浪带著你
You're gonna have to time it!
你得算准时间
You're gonna come right here, right to me!
你要过来这里，来我这壬
Five...four....
五 、 四……
Three...two...one.
一  一 一和， -一
Don't touch it! Don't touch that!
别碰 ! 别乱碰 !
This is a reminder of the young surfer...
这是纪念一位年轻的了生浪手
..who gave his life for the sport he loved.
为他热爱的运动南出生命
There you are.
你在这壬啊
I can't believe it! 1 can't believe it.
我真不敢相信
You came back.
你回来了
You saved my life, man. Thank you.
你救了我，谢谢你
Hey, hey, come on. You're gonna tip us!
拜旗，你会害我们翻船的
Well, I lost.
我输了
Me too.
我也是
Come on. Let's go, loser.
我们走吧，倒数第一
You want to help me out here?
帮有我苍开这里吧
You know the routine. Come on. Long. That's it. Smooth, you know. Come on.
你知道的老方法 慢慢滑，很好，顺著走
Young Joey MacEnroe was a beacon for a new generation.
年轻的故内社是年轻人的典范
May he rest in peace.
愿他一路好走
So, what am I bid for the board? Who'll give me 30? 30, come on.
来将标这埃浪板吧? 3 0 元起标
-Don't touch his stuff, man. -Pal, if you want to bid--
-别乱碰他的东西 -朋友，想抢标的话…
-Give me that. -Hey--!
-给我啦 一你…
Hey. Hey, everyone.
嘿，大家好啊
-How you been? -Oh, my gosh!
-你们好吗? -我的老天莹
-Yeah... -Hey, man, that's Z.
-老天，是乙钟 -没错，真的是我
..that's me.
真的是我
Skank, what's happening, man?
娃娃车，怎大啦?
Got a little sand in your egg sac there, fella.
小福福进沙子唾?
-Where have you been, Z? -What happened?
-你跑去哪了，乙印? -发生什么事了?
Oh, you know...
这个嘛
..1 got lost for a little while. But that kid there, Cody...
我训气了一委子 不过那个小鬼，酷弟
.. he pointed the way back.
他为我指引回来的方向
Could you please shut that off? Could you give me a minute?
先别拍好吗 ? 给我一点隐私
Check it out! How about this?
照过来 ! 我很神吧 ?
You want to talk about talent scout? People find talent.
什么叫终极星探 ? 我发据人才
I bring them back from the dead. The now living legend, ladies and--
还让他们起死回生 一起欢迎不死传奇…
-Shut up. -What? Shut up?
-闭嘴 -什么? 并跑?
I'm not a legend. I'm a guy looking for some nice waves, some good friends.
我不是传奇人物 我只是喜欢街街浪、交交朋友
Hey, guys, the swell is happening over on the north shore!
各位，北洪的浪很棒唾
I'm right behind you, Z.
我随和后就到
Ouch, that hurt.
唉哟 ! 很痛那
Come back here! You don't just walk away! Come on!
给我回来 ! 你们不能就这样走掉
He's taking this loss pretty hard.
各位，看来翰掉对他打击很大
Tank, how does it feel to lose after nine time--
坦克，九右胶之后落败感觉…
l wasn't kissing her. You can't have her!
我没有亲她 你们不能抢走她
Can we get a few words?
-雨位，可以说线句话吧?9 -你好，轧小九
You gave up the trophy to help Joe. What's that about?
你放素奖鼻帮助焦焦，为什么?
You know, Rob, that's what friends do.
麻吉就该这样嘛
-How's it feel to win, Joe? -l won?
-第一名感觉怎样，焦焦? -我得第一?
Come on! I'll tell my mom. Gimme. Gimme!
我要去告我妈喔，还人家…
Oh, Lia! Oh, Lia.
痢亚 ! 莉亚
Don't you walk away from me! lam Reggie Belafon--
不准你们走掉，我是雷大确
Turn that thing off. Mikey! You are so fired!
给我关机，米基，你被炒角急了
I can't imagine a better day.
再好不过啦 !
Dude, this-- This whole experience has just been--
这整个经验真是…
It's amazing. Z?
太和神奇了，Z负?
I don't think I've ever had a better friend to me in my life.
他是我这草子最珍贵的朋友了
It's just really cool to have everything I need.
能撞有这一切真的钟呆了
-Don't do it. Help! -Arnold!
-不要啦 ! 救人喔! -虽1阿诺!
To be honest, man, I'm kind of, like, bored of talking about myself.
说真的，我有谈腻我自己了
So, is that cool? You guys got what you need?
可以了吗? 你们拍到你们要的了吧
-We got it -All right. Be good!
-拍完了 -钙，保重唾
Cowabunga!
生浪蕊藏 !
Of course we're proud of him!
我们当然以他为例 哪个母亲不会以他为傲?
We're so full of proudness.
我们都鸥有全站
You know what? He followed his dream...
他追等自己的萝想
..and he went out there, and now he's coming home with the trophy.
出国比赛，拿冠军，光荣回家
l can't wait to see his trophy.
我等不及要看奖番
There's not really a trophy.
其实没有奖番陡
Is there, like, a big shell or something like that?
那有上贝胡痪牌还是什么的吗?
There's no shell. There's no trophy. Well, he didn't win.
没忠贞、没痪番，他没赢耶
What?
什么?
How bad was it? Did he get smoked?
葵得多收 ? 他被打成落水鸟?
-He was in the finals. -Second place? That's losing.
-他进了决赛 -第二名 ? 那就是翰啦
-Winning is not everything, Glen. -Right.
-赢不代表一切，可人 -是哦
Look at what Cody did--
看看酷弟的成就
Go back to the "winning isn't everything" thing.
你说啥“赢不代表一切”?
That doesn't compute, really.
那甸话太做作了
You know what, Glen? I really hope someday you can be more like Cody.
我真希望你哪天能和酷弟多学点
This interview is over.
访谈结束了
Remember when were talking about you leaving? That was great.
我们说访谈已经结束，记得吗?9
Remember when you were gonna go?
你们不是收一收要走了吗?
-We were gonna go-- -You should still go.
-我们是要走啦 -你们还是得流
I know what I'm doing. I can unplug one of your little Hollywood devices.
我知道我在干嘛 我能拆了这些好莱雹设备
The lighting thing, whatever you call that...
像这个燃，管它叫什条
..and then the microphone thing.
还有上驮克风
Go back to Hollywood.
滚回好莱雹去吧
Cody would never do this.
酷弟就不会这样